(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T13:20:36.135082",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
聞いた風に煽られて
Stirred by the howling wind,
流す涙を隠しつつ
hiding my flowing tears,
明日に駆け出した
I dashed toward tomorrow,
わため将軍
General Watame!
東に亡き人のいるときは
When thinking of someone lost in the east,
生皮で押さえた判切を
I pressed a damp seal with raw hide...
西に飢えた人がいりゃ、我が身すら惜しない
And when someone hungers in the west, I wouldn't spare myself.
人の世は悲しきものと
Though the human world is sorrowful,
羊のわためじゃ味気なし、されど、少女の笑顔奪わば
A sheep like Watame makes it dull. Yet, if you steal a maiden's smile,
あちくしょう以下の罪悪感、退治してくれよう、わため将軍
I'll purge that guilt worse than a bastard's—General Watame!
走れ！富の奥山どどどどど
Run! Deep into the mountains of wealth, dododododo!
歌え！浅き夢みじんめめめ
Sing! In fleeting, shattered dreams, memememe!
蓋にきらめく太陽は、雲の上で燃えているか
Is the sun glittering on the lid burning above the clouds?
明日に駆け出した
I dashed toward tomorrow,
わため将軍
General Watame!
イエーイ！
Yay!
こんばんは！どどどーんと！ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためでーす！おー！
Good evening! Dododon! Hololive 4th Gen, Tsunomaki Watame here! Oh!
みんなー！
Everyone!
見に来てくれて、ありがとー！
Thank you for coming to watch!
今日は、誰の、誰の、誕生日でしょうか？わためのお誕生日です！
Whose birthday is it today, whose birthday could it be? It's Watame's birthday!
とゆーことで、今日はしゃあぷわためのお誕生日2021で、たくさんツイートしていただけると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
So today, for "Sharp Watame's Birthday 2021", I'd be so happy if you tweeted a lot! Thank you so much!
やれやれ、誕生日が始まっちまったぜ。
Good grief, my birthday has finally started.
なあ、どんな1日になるのかなあ？楽しみだなあ！
I wonder what kind of day it'll be? I'm so excited!
お祝い、たくさんお祝いありがとうね！おめでとうありがとうね！
Thank you so much for all the birthday celebrations! Thank you for the congratulations!
いやこれ、ちょっと1時間ぐらいありますんでね、見てってね、楽しんでってね。
Well, this stream is about an hour long, so please watch and enjoy!
最後まで絶対見てね！頼む！頼む！一生のお願い！
Make sure to watch till the very end! Please! Please! I'm begging you for life!
うそ
No way
うそっ
Really?
あれ、今日は…
Huh, today...
あの…お、おれ？
Um... m-me?
きょ、今日は、あれ？
T-Today, huh?
なんか、あの…誰かからお、お、お呼ばれする予定なんだけどな
I'm supposed to be, um... invited somewhere by someone, you know.
わため先輩！
Watame-senpai!
あ！
Ah!
この声は、ぽ、ボタンちゃん！
That voice... B-Botan-chan!
ちょっと行ってくるわ！
I'm going to go check it out!
行ってきまーす！
See ya!
わため先輩！
Watame-senpai!
はーい！
Hiiii!
ようこそ私の研究室へ。
Welcome to my laboratory.
なんか、怖いから将軍の格好で来たよ。
It was scary, so I came dressed as a shogun.
あ…
Ah...
本当だ、武装してる！
You're right, you're armed!
武装してきたよ！
I came armed!
じゃき、将軍じゃオーブンに入れない…入らないじゃないか、オーブン…
Wait, as a shogun you can't fit in the oven... wait, wouldn't you fit in the oven...
あの、わため先輩ちょっと大変言いにくいんですが、あの、そのかぶとちょっと脱いでもらえませんか？
Um, Watame-senpai, this is a bit hard to say, but could you please take off that kabuto helmet?
いや、オーブンって言われて、これ、え？
Wait, you said oven, so... huh?
あ、あの違います。お、オー、オーブンじゃ、オーブンじゃないです。オーブンじゃないです。今日オーブン使わない？使わないです。本当に？
Ah, um, no. O-, ov-, oven- no, not an oven. Not an oven. We're not using an oven today? We're not. Really?
はい。
Yes.
脱いでもだいじょうぶ？
Is it okay if I take it off?
だいじょうぶです、だいじょうぶです。
It's okay, it's okay.
だいじゅぶ、だいじゅ、だいじょうぶです。
It's fine, it's fi-, it's fine.
じゃ、脱ぐか、な。あの、ちょっと脱いで、脱いで。ぽいっ、ぽいっ。
Then I'll take it off, right. Um, just take it off, take it off. Toss, toss.
あー、よかった！今日ちょっと私の、あ、だいじょうぶだ、だいじょうぶです。だいじょうぶですよ！だいじょうぶだな、だいじょうぶです。今日私のね、ホームへようこそお越しいただきました。
Ah, glad to hear it! Welcome to my home today.
キッチンがあるんだね。
There's a kitchen.
あ、今日ちょっとね、キッチンね、急遽ちょっとこしらえたんですよ。
Ah, today, um, we hastily put together a kitchen.
急遽？急遽？今日なんか、あ、なんか、なんか誰かの誕生日って言うのを聴いて…
Hastily? Hastily? Today, um, I heard it was someone's birthday...
あー、なんか、ちょ、キッチンあったほうがいいのかなと思って。
Ah, I thought it might be good to have a kitchen.
あ、なるほど、その人のために？
Ah, I see, for that person?
そうですね。ま、やっぱり誕生日といえば、美味しい料理に、
That's right. Well, after all, when it comes to birthdays, delicious food,
もちろんね。ケーキとかね。
Of course. Like cake.
そうなんだね。そう、だからちょっとケーキを作りたいなと思ったんです。なのでちょっとこうね、
Is that so. So, I thought I'd like to make a cake. That's why, um,
手作り？
Homemade?
そうなんです。
That's right.
そうなんです、キッチンをこしらえたわけなんです。なるほど。ケーキは？ただ、ケーキを作る前に、まあね、せっかくこうやってわため先輩がさ、一緒に、うんうん、キッチンの周りにいいてくれるということで、もっとやりたいことをね、
That's why we put together a kitchen. I see. The cake? But before making the cake, since Watame-senpai is here with me around the kitchen, there are things I want to do more...
何？やりたいことあります？
What? Is there something you want to do?
やっぱこれなの？
Is it this?
やりたいこと？
Things you want to do?
なるほど。
I see.
じゃあ、なのでちょっとついてきてもらっていいですかね。
So, could you please follow me for a bit?
場所移動します。
We're changing locations.
さき行って？
Go ahead?
あ、先行ったほうがいいですか？
Ah, should I go ahead?
しょうがないな。じゃあちょっと、
Can't be helped. Well then,
うん、ついてきてください。
Yeah, please follow me.
こっちです。
This way.
大丈夫なんだな。足元気をつけてください。
Are you okay? Please watch your step.
優しい。
How kind.
この日の上…この日の上の屋上までちょっと、
On top of this sun... up to the rooftop above this sun...
なんでここ燃えてんの？
Why is it burning here?
こわー！
Scary!
いや、香ばしい匂いしてきたましね。
Well, a savory smell has started coming.
いややっぱりね、あの建物の中で今煙ってちょっと厳しいんですよ。
Well, inside the building right now, smoke is a bit tough.
そうなんだね。
Is that so.
そうそう。だからやっぱりちょっと屋上でね。
That's right. So on the rooftop.
あ、煙…あ、煙出すなら屋上ですから。
Ah, smoke... if we're making smoke, it's on the rooftop.
煙出すなら屋上…？はじめてできる、やべ、やべやべやべ。
Rooftop for smoke...? First time doing it, oops, oops.
やべやべ！聞こえてるぞ！じゃーん！私のでございます。
Oops! You can hear me! Ta-da! Here is mine.
はじめてきたね、ここ！はじめてきた！
We came here for the first time! First time here!
屋上結構いいでしょ？
The rooftop is pretty nice, right?
いいね、開放感があって。
Nice, with an open feeling.
いいね、ひらいね。
Nice, spacious.
でしょ？
Right?
ここで何をするっていうのかね。
What are we going to do here?
ま、やっぱりね、わあた、これ？い…違う！違う！
Well, after all, Wata-, this? N... No! No!
やっぱり、ま、わため先輩といえば私の中では、まあ、歌っていうのもありますので、
After all, when talking about Watame-senpai, for me, well, there's singing too,
ちょっと今日は一緒に歌えたらいいなと。
I thought it would be nice if we could sing together today.
お！
Oh!
いいですかね？いいですか、逆に一緒に歌っていただけるんですか？
Is that okay? Is it okay, can we actually sing together?
ぜひ、お願いします。
By all means, please.
やったー！
Yay!
というわけで、今日はわため先輩と一緒に歌わせていただきます。
So today, I'll be singing together with Watame-senpai.
ラジオ体操、ラジオ体操お願いします！
Radio calisthenics, please!
私がゲストみたい。
I feel like a guest.
お願いします！
Please!
じゃあ、いきますか。はい。せーの！やさしい気持ち！
Well, shall we go? Yes. Ready! Yasashii Kimochi!
泣けない女の やさしい気持ちを
You'll learn a lot about the tender feelings
あなたがたくさん 知るのよ
of a girl who can't cry,
無邪気な心で 私を笑顔へ
With an innocent heart, guide me to a smile
導いてほしいの ぎゅっと私を抱きしめ
I want you to hold me tight in your arms.
そう いいかげんな男が あなたの理想だとしても
Even if an irresponsible guy is your ideal,
この愛は 自由をこわすって？
will this love destroy freedom...?
少しだけあなたが優しくなった日は
The day you were a little bit kinder to me
それはあたしに不安がのしかかる日
is the day anxiety weighs heavily on me.
あなたの膝に手を乗せるのは
Putting my hand on your knee
譲り合わない体温全て感じたいから
is to feel all of your unyielding body warmth.
思うだけで不都合だらけになる心
My heart becomes full of inconveniences just by thinking.
そんな恋人同士酷くおかしい
Such lovers are terribly strange.
お願いあたしを他の子と一緒に束ねたりしないで
Please, don't bundle me together with other girls.
融通利かない女だと言って放っといたりしないで
Don't call me an inflexible woman and leave me be.
可愛いもんよ好きだと言ってくれたなら
I can be cute if you tell me you love me.
遠回りしすぎだよあなたのお喋り
Your chit-chat takes too many detours.
言葉で計れないのは解いていても欲しい物
Things unmeasured by words are still what I want you to untie.
想えば思うほど空回りする心
The more I think, the more my heart spins in circles.
気付いているなら早く抱いてキスして
If you notice, hurry and hold me, kiss me.
お願いあたしの真っ直ぐなこの愛を見捨てたりしないで
Please don't abandon this straightforward love of mine.
「あと15分!」の口癖を今夜はは大目に見て
Overlook my habit of saying "Just 15 more minutes!" tonight.
愛しい人よ
My beloved,
くるくると表情を変えながらあたしの手の平の上にいてね
Change your expression endlessly and stay in my palm.
想えば思うほど空回りする心
The more I think, the more my heart spins in circles,
気付いているなら早く抱いてキスして
If you notice, hurry and hold me, kiss me.
お願いあたしの他の子と一緒に束ねたりしないで
Please, don't bundle me together with other girls.
融通利かない女だと言って放っといたりしないで
Don't call me an inflexible woman and leave me be.
可愛いもんよ好きだと言ってくれたなら
I can be cute if you tell me you love me.
お願いぎゅっとあたしを抱きしめて もうあたしを離さないで
Please hug me tight and never let me go again.
お願いあたしを他の子と一緒に束ねたりしないで
Please, don't bundle me together with other girls.
会っても鳴ってもキスしてもいいから色々してたいわ
Whether we meet, ring, or kiss, I want to do various things.
もうあたしを止めないで もうあたしを止めないで
Don't stop me anymore, don't stop me anymore.
あ！あ！
Ah! Ah!
やべ、台詞忘れた！
Crap, I forgot my lines!
誰か忘れた。
Who did I forget?
え？
Eh?
ちょっと買ってきていいですか？
Can I go buy some?
え、急だね。
Huh, that's sudden.
あの、何味がいいですか？
Um, what flavor do you want?
誰？
Who?
誰です。
Who is it.
必要それ。
Is that necessary?
必要です。
It's necessary.
必要？
Necessary?
必要です。んじゃ、おろしがいいかな。
Then grated daikon might be good.
オッケーです。
Okay.
大根おろしがいい。
Grated daikon is good.
大根たっぷり買ってきます。
I'll go buy plenty of daikon.
おお、いってらっしゃい。急に大根買いに行く人おる？
Who suddenly goes to buy daikon?
あ、だめ！
Ah, no!
はちゃまー！はちゃまーのはちゃまーのはちゃまーの残像が見える！
I can see Haachama's afterimages!
ちょっと行ってくるわ。
I'll go check it out.
はちゃまー！はちゃまー！
Haachama! Haachama!
おお、羊のよーどんへいらっしゃい！
Oh, welcome to Sheep's Yoodon!
今日ね、あのわためをね、出荷するためにね、ま、ここに呼んできましたと。
Today, to ship Watame, we invited her here.
出荷って何ですか？
What do you mean by shipping out?
お誕生日おめでとー！ありがとう！お誕生日おめでとー！ありがとう！
Happy birthday! Thank you!
出荷やだ！出荷、出荷！出荷やだ！
I don't want to be shipped!
あ、そんなこと言ってね、ま、さすが生誕もね。誕生日のね、わためにね、そんな出荷なんてね、しないわよ、本当に。
I wouldn't really ship you off for your birthday.
そうだよね！
That's right!
そんなね、鬼じゃないからね。だから、はつうま、ケーキを作ってきました！
I'm not that cruel. So Haachama made a cake!
やったー！ケーキを作った？
Yay! You made a cake?
うん。何入ってんのかな？
Yeah. What's inside?
ケーキ作ってきたよー！
I made a cake!
色んな愛も込めて、色んなたくさん愛も込めて作ってきたんで。
I made it with lots and lots of love put into it.
何入れた？チーズケーキだっけ？何入れた？
What did you put in? Was it cheesecake? What did you put in?
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
おおおお！チーズケーキだね。
Whoa! It's a cheesecake.
チーズケーキだね。
It's a cheesecake, right?
チーズケーキかな？
Is it a cheesecake?
かな？たぶん。かな？
Is it? Probably. Is it?
あーーー！フォークだなぁ！
Ahhh! A fork!
うーー！やるの！
Ugh! Take that!
やるの！
Take that!
ケーキ、食べたい？食べたい！
Do you want to eat the cake? I want to!
あ、そんなに食べたいなら……
Oh, if you want to eat it that badly...
うん、してほしい？うん、してほしい。
Hm, want me to? Yeah, I want you to.
うし、うりゃ！
Yay, take that!
ちゃんと、あのー……刺して、刺して。
Make sure, um... poke it, poke it.
ほら、取れない。
Look, I can't grab it.
あ、取れた！ナイス、ナイス、ナイス。
Ah, got it! Nice, nice, nice.
はい。
Here.
あーーー！もう、も、もう！やめ、やめ、やめ、やめ！
Aahh! Stop, stop, stop, stop!
美味しい？はちゃも食べるの、これ？
Is it good? Are you going to eat it too, Hato?
え、えいっ！しょ。
E-ehy! Heave-ho.
はい、どうぞ。あぐあぐあぐあぐ……美味いね！
Here you go. Nom nom nom... Delicious!
美味い、美味い。なんかもう一個取れたわ。どうぞ。
Delicious, delicious. I got another one. Here you go.
あぐあぐあぐあぐ……どうぞ、あぐあぐあぐあぐ……はい、美味い！
Nom nom nom... Here, nom nom... Yup, delicious!
美味い、美味い。はい、もぐもぐ。
Delicious, delicious. Yup, munch munch.
ありがとう、ケーキ。いぇーい！
Thank you, cake. Yay!
ケーキ、バイバイ。
Cake, bye-bye.
永久に甘いの残ってて……いいのかな？ケーキバイバイ。
It'll stay sweet forever... Is that okay? Cake, bye-bye.
あ、もぐもぐ。あ、なんか落ちちゃった。あら、何なった？
Ah, munch munch. Oh, something dropped. Oh, what happened?
じゃあ、そろそろ歌おうか？
Shall we sing soon?
なんか全てが急なんだけど！歌うか、じゃあそろそろ歌おうか！
Everything is so sudden! Shall we sing, well, let's sing soon!
え、でもここじゃちょっとさ、なんか雰囲気出ないと思うんだよ。
Um, but I don't think we'll get much of an atmosphere here.
え、わためちゃん、どっかに連れてってくれるの？
Eh, Watame-chan, are you going to take me somewhere?
いいよ、じゃあ、ちょっと一緒にジャンプして。
Sure, then let's jump together.
あ、オッケー！
Ah, okay!
せーの！
Ready, go!
はーーー！でん！わためのお家！いらっしゃいませー！
Haaa! Tada! Watame's house! Welcome!
やったー！
Yay!
呼びたかったんだよなー。えへへー！
I wanted to invite you here. Ehehe!
瞬間移動。
Instant teleportation.
てかなんか、ここ夜？夜じゃないよそれ。
Wait, is it night here? That's not night.
ま、形夜っぽいけど。木がね。
Well, it looks kind of night-ish. The trees.
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー。ここで歌うのかい？
Okay. Are we singing here?
干渉しとくよ、ハッチョマは。
I'll handle the interference, Hatchoma.
誰がだよ。一緒に歌うんだから。
Who are you calling that? We're singing together.
オッケー。デュエットするんだから。
Okay. We're doing a duet.
デュエットする？デュエットする？デュエットする？しよう。
Shall we duet? Shall we duet? Let's do it.
頼む。何の歌歌う？
Please. What song shall we sing?
あれだろ。例の、例のあれ歌う？
You know. That one, are we singing that one?
じゃあ、行く？行く行く行く行く？
Then, shall we go? Go, go, go, go?
もういっちゃん？いっちゃん？いっちゃん？
Already first one? First one? First one?
行くのか行かないのか、行くのか行かないのか……デュエット？
Are we going or not, are we going or not... Duet?
準備できたよー。
I'm ready.
オッケー。
Okay.
せーの！ハッピーシンセサイザー！
Ready, go! Happy Synthesizer!
ハッピーシンセサイザー 君の 胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, to the depths of your heart
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you
微か散った淡い片思い
A fleeting, pale unrequited love
笑い話だね 今となれば
It's just a joke, now that we're together
見る物全て 輝いて見えた
Everything I see shines brightly
あの日々がキレイに 笑ってるよ
Those days are smiling beautifully
我慢する事だけ 覚えなきゃいけないの？
Do I have to remember only to endure?
「大人になって頂戴ね？」 ならなくていいよ
"Please grow up?" No, if you don't want to
知らない事ばかり 知らないなんて言えなくて
So much I don't know, but I couldn't say so
「大変お似合いで」 ウソついてゴメンね
"What a nice couple" I'm sorry I lied
ハッピーシンセサイザー 君の 胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, to the depths of your heart
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you
つまらない「たてまえ」や 嫌なこと全部
Boring things you need to do, will all go away
消してあげるから この音で
by this sound
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一つ
I can't do much, but there's just one little thing
少しだけど 出来る事
I can do only for you
心躍らせる 飾らない言葉
Your heart will dance with every honest word
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll tell you in electronic sound
ハッピーシンセサイザー ほらね 楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, you see, it's much more fun
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
I hope your tears go away
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない? 別に
You don't need to act tough like that
自分に素直になれればいい
Just be true to yourself
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一つ
I can't do much, but there's just one little thing
少しだけど 出来る事
I can do only for you
ちょっと照れるような 単純な気持ち
My cheeks turn red with every simple feeling
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll tell you in electronic sound
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね 楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see? It'll be fun.
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
Playing a melody to wipe your tears away.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない 別に
You don't have to act so tough, you know.
自分に素直になればいい
Just be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄もない 僕に唯一つ
With nothing special about me, just one thing—
少しだけど出来ること
Something small I can do.
ちょっと照れるような 単純な気持ち 電子音で伝えるよ
Simple feelings that make me a bit shy, conveyed in electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, reaching deep into your heart.
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
Playing a melody that will reach you.
つまらない建前や 嫌なこと全部
Boring formalities and all unpleasant things—
消してあげるから この音で
I'll erase them all with this sound.
何の取り柄もない 僕に唯一つ
With nothing special about me, just one thing—
少しだけど出来ること
Something small I can do.
心踊らせる 飾らない言葉 電子音で伝えるよ
Simple words that make your heart dance, conveyed in electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね 楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see? It'll be fun.
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
Playing a melody to wipe your tears away.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない 別に
You don't have to act so tough, you know.
自分に素直になればいい
Just be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄もない 僕に唯一つ
With nothing special about me, just one thing—
少しだけど出来ること
Something small I can do.
ちょっと照れるような 単純な気持ち 電子音で伝えるよ
Simple feelings that make me a bit shy, conveyed in electronic sounds.
楽しかったね！楽しかった！
That was fun! It was so fun!
にゃー！
Meow!
あ、ただいまー！
Ah, welcome back!
お帰り！あれ？わたげちゃん？
Welcome back! Huh? Watame-chan?
確かに この場所
Sure enough, in this place...
匂いでなんか分かっちゃった
I could kind of tell by the smell.
匂いで分かっちゃった！
You could tell by the smell?!
匂いで分かっちゃった。え、これわための地元？
I could tell by the smell. Eh, is this Watame's hometown?
そうだよ！やべ、ばれた！
That's right! Oh crap, I've been found out!
また遊びに来るよ！
I'll come play again!
ばれた、ばれた！
Busted, busted!
生息地がばれた！ また遊びに来ちゃおうかな！
My habitat was found out! Maybe I'll come back to play again!
連絡先教えてよ
Give me your contact info!
連絡先教えて
はあちゃま後で連絡先渡すね
Haachama, I'll give you my contact info later, okay?
おっけーおっけー
Okay, okay!
じゃあさ、今日が最後になるかもしれないからさ
So, since today might be the last time...
記念撮影す……記念撮影たくさんしよっかな
Let's take lots of commemorative photos...
しよっか！
Let's do it!
うん、すんごいショットに挑戦してもいいんだよ
Yeah, you can try out some crazy shots, you know.
いいですよ
Sounds good.
じゃあ3人でまず……あ、撮る？
Then first with the three of us... Ah, you taking it?
どのポーズがいい？
What pose should we do?
どうする？なんかコメントとかでも、あ、そうね
What should we do? Maybe from comments too—ah, right.
見たいポーズとかあったらぜひ
If you have any poses you want to see, definitely let us know.
何がいい？
What do you want?
何がいい？ 草しかねえよ
What do you want? There's nothing but grass!
そのポーズ！
That pose!
草なんポーズ！草なんポーズ！
Grass pose! Grass pose!
草、草、わさ、わさ、なんだこれ
Grass, grass, wasa, wasa, what is this?
せっかくだからさ！ せっかく
Since we have the chance! Since—
せっかく集まったんで草のポーズ！草のポーズ！
Since we're all gathered, the grass pose! The grass pose!
いい？
Is that good?
なんかある？
Anything else?
ある、あ、わため先輩なんかあります？ 撮りたいやつ
There is—ah, Watame-senpai, do you have any? One you want to take.
ツノドリル
Horn Drill.
ツノドリル！
Horn Drill!
ツノドリル！食らってじゃあツノドリル
Horn Drill! Take that, then Horn Drill.
あ、いいよ。うわーって言って
Ah, sure. Go 'Wah!' and—
まだやってない、まだやってない、まだやってない
Not yet, not yet, not yet!
まだやってない、まだやってない
Not yet, not yet!
行くよ？
Ready?
はい。ツノドリル！
Okay. Horn Drill!
したから、ぐわー！
From below, Gwaa!
愉快愉快！
Hilarious, hilarious!
愉快愉快！これ気持ちいい！
Hilarious, hilarious! This feels great!
これでいいの？
Is this good?
いいのか？
Is it?
よかったよかった。
Good, good.
ちょっと、やられた後でいいのか？
Wait, is it okay right after getting attacked?
地元でいいのかこんな喧嘩して
Is it okay in your hometown to fight like this?
いやいや違う違う。
No no, wait.
チワワのポーズ！ チワワのポーズ！
Chihuahua pose! Chihuahua pose!
やばい、やばい、やばい、ごめんなさい！
Oh no, oh no, oh no, I'm sorry!
やばい！ ツノドリル！
Oh no! Horn Drill!
このままハート作ろうよ。
Let's make a heart just like this.
あ、いいよ。
Ah, sure.
ハート作ろう！ ハート作ろう！
Let's make a heart! Let's make a heart!
命大事に？
Prioritize your life?
うん、命大事に。命大事に。
Yeah, prioritize life. Prioritize life.
なんか回復してきた。
I've recovered a bit.
あ、本当？
Ah, really?
よかったよかった。
Good, good.
HP！ HP！
HP! HP!
いやいや回復しちゃ、回復しちゃダメ！
No no, you shouldn't recover!
ひどいね。
That's awful.
ツーショットとか？
A two-shot or something?
あ、じゃあツーショットを取る。私あれするよ、カメラマンするよ
Ah, then we'll take a two-shot. I'll do that—I'll be the cameraman.
シシロカメラマン？ シシロカメラマンにちょっと
Shishiro cameraman? To Shishiro cameraman, let's—
頼みましょ。
Let's ask.
シシロカメラマン、下から行くアングルだけどいいかな？
Shishiro cameraman, is an angle from below okay?
え？どういうこと？
Eh? What do you mean?
シシロカメラマンは下から？
Shishiro cameraman from below?
いやー！パンツ見せないで！
No—! Don't show our panties!
下から行くよ！
Going from below!
いやー！
No—!
見ちゃダメ！
Don't look!
いや、いや、いや！
No, no, no!
見せんな！見せんな！やめて、こんなの！
Don't show it! Don't show it! Stop this!
そんなショット……
What kind of shot is that...
あんな あんな カメラに映してって
"Look, look, capture it on camera!"
ここ ここも映してって
"Capture here too!"
うわあ 撮れた 撮れた！
"Whoa, I got it, I got it!"
あ ダブルピース？
"Ah, double peace?"
あ ダブルピース？ あ いいね！
"Ah, double peace? Ah, nice!"
いえーい！
"Yay!"
はい！
"Right!"
いいね！いいね！
"Nice! Nice!"
はい！
"Right!"
なでキスして なでキス
"Pat and kiss, pat and kiss."
なでキス
"Pat and kiss."
あ こっちに ま ま ま
"Ah, over here, m-m-m..."
ま ま ま ま ま
"M-m-m-m-m..."
どう どう？ いいね！
"How is it? Nice!"
いい感じ！
"Feels good!"
いい感じよ！
"Feels great!"
やっぱね ちょっと
"As expected, you know, a bit..."
後ろとかも なんかこう 横とか後ろとか
"From behind too, like, from the side or behind."
あ こっちか
"Ah, this way?"
こっち？
"This way?"
こっち こっち
"This way, this way."
あ こっちだった？
"Ah, was it this way?"
どっち どっち？ こっち こっち
"Which way? This way, this way."
こっち？
"This way?"
こっち？ じゃあ 私こっち向く？
"This way? Then should I face this way?"
あ じゃあ 振り向いてよ 振り向いてよ
"Ah, then turn around, turn around."
いいよ
"Sure."
振り向け じゃあね
"Turn around, you see."
呼んでんじゃん
"You're calling us."
二人とも こっち向いて！
"Both of you, face this way!"
何？
"What?"
え どうしたの？
"Eh, what's wrong?"
みんな右から向いちゃったな
"Everyone turned from the right side."
ああ あ こっち？
"Ah, ah, this way?"
こう こう
"Like this, like this."
二人で ふあーって
"Both of you, like whoosh."
オッケー
"Okay."
二人とも
"Both of you"
こっち向いて
"Face this way"
やあー！
"Yay!"
ああ かわいい！
"Ah, cute!"
これ かわいい！
"This is cute!"
いいね！
"Nice!"
いえーい！
"Yay!"
チーズ 交換する？
"Cheese, shall we swap?"
あ 交換する？
"Ah, swap?"
オッケー じゃあ みんな見てろ
"Okay, then everyone watch."
一旦私して
"First, let me do it."
オッケー オッケー
"Okay, okay."
女のが撮りたい！
"I want to take a girl's!"
何がいい？
"What's good?"
どんなのがいい？
"What kind is good?"
やっぱローアングルから？
"As expected, from a low angle?"
ローアングル？
"Low angle?"
あ そんなー！
"Ah, no way!"
そんなー！ そんなー！ やめてください！
"No way! No way! Please stop!"
やめてください！ いいよ！
"Please stop! Sure!"
やめてください！
"Please stop!"
やったー！
"Yay!"
あ 後ろからも撮った？
"Ah, did you take from behind too?"
後ろ撮る？
"Take from behind?"
オッケー
"Okay."
じゃあね
"See ya."
あ あ わかった わかった
"Ah, ah, I get it, I get it."
狙われてる なんてんだ 食べられそうになったらわためっていう構造やろ
"Being targeted, what is it, if you look like you're about to be eaten, that's Watame's structure, right?"
あ いいね
"Ah, nice."
いい いい
"Good, good."
こっち こっち
"This way, this way."
どっち？
"Which way?"
わため わためさまこっちじゃない？
"Watame, Watame-sama isn't this way?"
こっち？
"This way?"
そうだね
"That's right."
ここで
"Here."
顔
"Face."
カメラ目線で
"Look at the camera."
うん
"Yeah."
こっちだ
"This way."
あ そうそうそうそう あ
"Ah, yes, yes, yes, yes, ah..."
顔やばい！
"My face is terrible!"
やばい！
"Terrible!"
あ いいよ！
"Ah, nice!"
いいよ いいよ！
"Nice, nice!"
あ おしまいだ
"Ah, it's over."
おしまいだ
"It's over."
おしまいだ！
"It's over!"
いい感じ いい感じ！
"Feels good, feels good!"
いいかい？
"Ready?"
あ いいよ いいよ オッケー オッケー オッケー
"Ah, nice, nice! Okay, okay, okay."
他のやつ撮りたい？
"Want to take another one?"
死ぬんだ…
"I'm dying..."
もっとなんか
"More like..."
なんか
"Something..."
ねの…手ぇのやつ？
"Neno... hand thing?"
お！
"Oh!"
いえーい！ いえーい！
"Yay! Yay!"
いいね！ いえーい！
"Nice! Yay!"
いえーい！
"Yay!"
ごめんね ごめんね
"Sorry, sorry."
ごめんね
"Sorry."
バリバリの服
"Crispy outfit."
大丈夫よ 洋服脱げない？
"It's fine, won't your clothes come off?"
放送事故だよ！
"That's a broadcasting accident!"
ちょっと わため様のお洋服バリバリちょっとマジックテープで貼ってたんだね
"Wait, Watame-san's outfit was crispy, stuck together with velcro."
マジックテープで貼ってたんだね
"Stuck together with velcro."
あ？
"Huh?"
なんだぁ？
"What the heck?"
あ この声はバカざるども？
"Ah, this voice is the idiot monkeys?"
あら
"Oh my."
もしかして
"Could it be..."
呼ばれちゃった！
"We got called!"
ちょっと呼ばれ組みたいだから一緒に寝てくるわ
"Since we look like the called group, I'm going to sleep together with them."
わかった！
"Understood!"
じゃあまたね！
"Then see you later!"
バイバーイ！
"Bye-bye!"
ありがとう！
"Thank you!"
ハッピーバースデー！
"Happy Birthday!"
ありがとう！
"Thank you!"
おめでとうございます！
"Congratulations!"
ありがとうございます！
"Thank you very much!"
わためー！ わためー！
"Watame! Watame!"
おお 来た来た来た来た！
"Oh, they're here, they're here!"
おー 懐かしい！
"Oh, nostalgic!"
遅いよー！
"You're late!"
お腹空かして待ってたんだからな！
"We were waiting with empty stomachs!"
そう おなかぺこぺこだよ
"Yeah, our stomachs are starving."
何食べる？
"What should we eat?"
人生スキンケッショウ？
"Life skin lotion?"
ほら そこ見て
"Look over there."
ケーキ？
"Cake?"
とりあえずケーキ ケーキ
"For now, cake, cake."
あ ケーキ ケーキ ケーキ ケーキ！
"Ah, cake, cake, cake, cake!"
食べる食べる食べるから そう ケーキ！
"Eating, eating, eating, so, cake!"
痩せる なん…
"Lose weight, wha..."
そう ケーキなんだ！ 痩せたい 痩せようの！
"Yeah, it's cake! I want to lose weight, let's lose weight!"
じゃ
"Well,"
ケーキを食べる前に
"Before eating cake,"
お腹を減らそうぜ！
"Let's empty our stomachs!"
お どうする？ もう運動が大事だね
"Oh, what should we do? Exercise is important."
大事大事だな
"That's right, important."
うん
"Yeah."
じゃあ 運動するぞ
"Then, let's exercise."
ラジオ体操かな？
"Radio calisthenics maybe?"
マジック！
"Magic!"
スタート！
"Start!"
自分よりツイてない誰か見て安心かい？
"Are you relieved seeing someone less fortunate than yourself?"
自分だけは例外思いたくて勝手言った
"You selfishly wanted to think that only you were the exception."
いつからか昼と夜が行き違った生活で
"Living a life where day and night somehow got crossed."
ふさぎこまないでどうか 目を覚まし 道を探せ
"Don't mope around, please wake up and find your way."
なんだかんだ叫んだって やりたいことやるべきです
"No matter what you shout, you should do what you want to do."
あなたなんだ次の番は やりがいあふれるレースで
"You're next, it's a race full of purpose."
寝不足にて疲労 疲れすぎてどうしようと
"Due to lack of sleep, fatigue, wondering what to do when too tired,"
うかがう顔色も気にしすぎたこの行動
"Carefully watching expressions too much in this action."
なんだかんだ叫んだって やりたいこと
"No matter what you shout, what you want to do..."
やりたいこと
"what you want to do"
世界中のすべての人間に好かれるなんて気持ち悪いよ
It's creepy to be liked by everyone in the world,
だけど一つになれない教室で 君と二人 手を繋いでいたいのだ
but I want to hold hands with you in a classroom where we can’t connect.
数の暴力に白旗をあげて 悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
I'll raise the white flag to the tyranny of the majority and say cheese.
ポストトゥルースの甘いディープキス エロく歪んでいるラブラブドピース
A sweet, post-truth French kiss—a warped, erotic love & peace.
自己中の光線銃 乱射する 強者のナンセンス
A self-centered ray gun firing wildly, the nonsense of the strong.
オートークチュールで作る 殺しのライセンス
An haute couture license to kill.
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム 無痛分娩で授かるベイブ
A game of musical chairs that created division, a baby born by epidural labor.
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
We’re calling a grandiose in-joke "history."
生きたいが死ねと言われ 死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to live, but I'm told to die; I want to die, but I'm told to live.
幸せ自慢はダメ? 不幸嘆いていてもダメ?
Is it wrong to boast of my happiness? Is it wrong to grieve over my unhappiness?
図々しい言葉を避け 明るい未来のために
I’m avoiding impudent words for our glorious future.
さんはい
One, two.
この世には息もできない人がたくさんいるんですよ
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
あちらが立てば こちらが立たず 譲り 奪い 守り 行き違い
If I’m true to one side, I’m false to the other; we give, we take, we protect, we misunderstand.
地雷原で立ち止まり 大人しく犬になるんだワン
I stop in the minefield, and obediently become a dog, woof!
I love you
息苦しい日々の水面下 ゆらゆらと燻る血の花
Under the surface of my suffocating days, a flower of blood smokes and flickers.
コンプレックスを武器に争う それぞれの都合と自由のため
We use our complexes as weapons to fight for our own convenience and freedom.
息を止めることを強制する
We obligate ourselves to hold our breath.
息が詰まる息が詰まる息が詰まる息が詰まる
I can’t breathe, I can’t breathe, I can’t breathe, I can’t breathe.
いいね、サンキュー！
Awesome, thank you!
あるべき初めにハリが なさ過ぎるテレビの前
A needle at the very beginning, right in front of the television.
平和ボケしてませんか?
Are you living in a peaceful stupor?
目を覚ませ今な ここで
Wake up right now, right here!
なんだかんだ叫んだって やりたいことやるべきです
Whatever you shout out, you should do what you want to do.
あんたなんだ 次の番は
You're next in line.
みんなに愛呼びかけて
Calling out with love to everyone.
なんだかんだ 夢見たって 問題ない世の中です
Whatever dreams you have, there's no problem in this world.
あんたなんだ 次の番は
You're next in line.
みんなに愛呼びかけて なんだかんだ 夢見たって 問題ない世の中です
Calling out with love to everyone, whatever dreams you have, there's no problem in this world.
旦那さんが 次の番だ 夢が叶う大気です
It's hubby's turn next, the atmosphere where dreams come true.
イエーイ！
Yay!
はーい！
Hi!
いやあ、楽しかった！
Man, that was fun!
楽しかった！
So much fun!
でも、選曲よ！
But man, that song choice!
なんだ？なんだ？この選曲は！
What is this song choice?!
いや、バッチリだったけども！
Well, it fit us perfectly though!
バッチリだったでしょ！
It totally fit us!
すごいマッチしてたよね！
It matched us so well!
みんなもそう思うよな？
Everyone thinks so too, right?
なあ！
Right?
な！いい曲なんだよな！
It's such a good song!
バッチリ似合ってたじゃんなあ！
It suited us so well, didn't it?
なんだかんだバッチリな選曲だね！
In the end, it was a spot-on song choice!
ねえ、とっても良かった！
Yeah, it was wonderful!
いやめっちゃ楽しかった！
Man, we had so much fun!
いやめっちゃよかった！
Yeah, super great!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
お疲れ！
Good job!
そうだ、そうだよ、まとめよう！
That's right, let's wrap this up!
今日はわための誕生日ですね！
Today is Watame's birthday, right?
ですね！
That's right!
ですね！やっとお迎えライブ一緒にね、やれたんですけども！
We finally got to do this birthday live together!
まあ、我々からね、やっぱりわために、記念すべき日なのでプレゼントを！
Well, from us to Watame, since it's a momentous day, we have a present!
用意しましたー！
We prepared one!
しました！
We did!
おー！そして、なんと！プレゼントを用意していまーす！
Oh! And what's more, we prepared a present!
プレゼントでーす！
Here's a present!
ということ値、たくさん持ってきてください！
So everyone, bring them out!
だんだん！え、本当に聞いてない！
Ta-da! Eh, I really didn't hear about this!
え、聞いてて！
Eh, listen up!
わあ、すごい！浮いてる浮いてる！
Wow, amazing! It's floating!
わようにプレゼントです！おめでとう！
A present for Watame! Congratulations!
フレアと私からのプレゼントだよ！おめでとう！
It's a present from Flare and me! Congratulations!
ええ！？何にも聞かされてなかったぞこれ！
Eh?! I wasn't told anything about this!
当たり前だろ、サプライズなんだからよ！
Of course not, it's a surprise!
え、何にも聞かされてなかった！
Eh, I wasn't told anything!
当たり前だろ、サプライズなんだからよ！
Of course not, it's a surprise!
言っちゃいみないだろ！
Don't just give it away!
そうだよ！
That's right!
ええー！？
EHH?!
おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations!
これ、開けていいの！？
Can I open this?!
開けていいよ！開けてもいいよ！
You can open it! Go ahead and open it!
開けたいの！
I want to open it!
いいよいいよいいよ！
Sure, go ahead!
しゃがんで開けて！
Squat down and open it!
しゃがんで開けているぞ！
She's opening it while squatting down!
しゃがんで開けていいよ！
You can squat down and open it!
ちょっとね、色とか言っちゃうとちょっとあれだから...
Wait, if we say what color it is, that might spoil it...
もう見て確認してもらって...
Just look and check it out yourself...
かわいい！
So cute!
かわいい！かわいいものがはいってるでしょ！
Cute! There's something cute inside, right?
わため似合うとと思ったんだよ！
I thought it would suit Watame!
ねぇ！いつの間に！？
Hey! When did this happen?!
いつ出るぬ！？いつだろうね！
When did it come out?! Who knows!
わふれやっちょっ と一緒にね...そう、わためどれがいいかな！
Flare and I together... Which one is good for Watame!
え、なんでこれ選んだの！？
Eh, why did you choose this?!
そう、選んだ！
That's right, I chose it!
よかった！
Yay!
よかった、取ってってくれー！
I'm so glad, please take it!
取ってね！ありがとう！
Take it, okay? Thank you!
ということでね、ワタメのライブと
So, this was Watame's live
ワタメのサプライズでしたー！
and Watame's surprise!
おめでとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
嬉しいんだー！
I'm so happy!
いやこの後でもワタメ歌うんだよ？
Wait, I'm gonna sing after this too!
はい！まだまだ
Yes! There's still more
盛り上がっていってくだ祭だ！
to get hyped up!
はーい！ありがとうございまーす！
Yay! Thank you so much!
プレゼントは置いといて
Leave the present there!
はーい！
Okay!
置いて、持ってっとこっか
Let's put it down and take it...
ワタメの部屋に
to Watame's room!
持ってっとこっか？てかもうパーって消えるかな？
Shall we take it? Or will it just disappear?
そこに置いとく？そこにおくか
Put it right there? Yeah, put it there.
あとでスタッフさんがいい感じに回収してくれるとありがたいまーす！
The staff will nicely clean it up for us!
ありがとう本当に！えーん！
Thank you so much! Sob!
いいんだよ！
It's okay!
嬉しいんだーん！
I'm so happy!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
記念撮影とかしてくんないかな？
Won't you take a commemorative photo?
いいのかい？
Is that okay?
お？いいのかな？
Oh? Is that okay?
みんな撮りたいよな？
Everyone wants to take one, right?
お？やっぱやるか！
Oh? Guess we're doing it!
もう撮らないのかと思ってたけど
I thought we were done!
まだまだ残ってあげて（笑）
There's still more left, haha!
田中マン！お願い！
Tanaka-man! Please!
一緒のお願い！
Do it together, please!
一緒にした！嘘嘘！嘘嘘！
We did it together! Just kidding!
じゃあ、ふたりと撮影するか！
Then, shall we take a photo with them?
お願いしまーす！取ってくれー！よーじょ！いえーい！
Please! Take it! Children! Yay!
いいね！いいね！いえーい！
Nice! Nice! Yay!
限界まで！いえーい！
To the limit! Yay!
チカホにされているかい？撮ってくれてますか？いえーい！
Are you taking pictures? Yay!
ぴょんぴょんリールスター！ぴょんぴょんリールスター！
Pyon-pyon Reeler Star! Pyon-pyon Reeler Star!
ピョンピョンリールスター！ピョンピョンリールスターしてくれー！
Pyon-pyon Reeler Star! Please do it!
ピョンピョンリールしてくれたのか、ラム！
Did you Pyon-pyon reel for us, ram?
取ってくれましたから！かな？かな？
Because you took it for us! Right? Right?
いえーい！いえーい！
Yay! Yay!
した！した！したぞ！オッケー！塩化を求め！
We did it! Okay! Seeking chloride!
いえーい！いえーい！
Yay! Yay!
や、いい感じじゃない？
Hey, isn't this nice?
夜は満足じゃ！
Night is satisfying!
よかったですね、ワタミヒメよ。
That's great, Princess Watame.
ここで終わりにしようか！
Let's end it here!
もう終わりか！もう終わりか！
It's already over! It's already over!
じゃあまた明日ね！
See you tomorrow then!
じゃあ頑張ってください、この後も。
Good luck with the rest of the stream.
頑張ってね！ありがとう！みんなに聞いてきた！
Good luck! Thank you! I asked everyone!
いえーい！じゃあ我らは行くか！我らは帰るか！
Yay! Well then, shall we go?
帰っちゃうか！
Are we going home?
そうだね！また後でね！また後でね！
That's right! See you later!
バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
みんなー！嬉しいんだー！
Everyone~! I'm so happy~!
もうボタンちゃんとかはーまとかバカたれどもに、あの時間あけてね、お祝いしてもらって、
Button-chan, Haah-ma, and the Bakatare idiots made time to celebrate with me...
本当に嬉しい！あと今時間あけてくれて、
I'm so truly happy! And right now, making time,
こうやって配信を見てくれてるみんなも本当にありがとうございます！
and watching the stream like this, thank you all so much!
いや、ここで泣いたら、いかんのよー
Man, if I cry here, that'd be bad.
本当にみんな、いつも応援してくれて、ありがとう！
Truly everyone, thank you always for supporting me!
ありがとう！このあとはね、大事な、大事なお知らせとか、あの、情報量たくさんありますので、
Thank you! After this, there's important announcements and lots of information,
ちょっとその前に、あの、ソロでも歌わせてもらったりして、
but just before that, letting me sing solo and all,
そのあと告知をさせてもらってもいいでしょうか？
would it be alright if I made some announcements after that?
コメント見てるで！
I'm reading the comments!
わー、スーパーチャットありがとうね！メンバーシップに入ってくれた人も本当にありがとうございます！
Waah, thank you for the super chats! And thank you so much to membership supporters!
サイリーム、あのスタンプで触れるので、よかったらいっぱい振ってっていってください！お願いします！
You can interact with cyalumes using stamps, so please shake them a lot! Please!
いいよ！いい玉ー！わ、いっぱい、いって！
Good! Good balls! Wow, go ahead!
じゃあ、ちょっと感謝の気持ちを込めて、歌わせていただきたいなと思います！
Well then, with gratitude in my heart, I'd like to sing a song for you!
まず1曲目！
First song!
山菅良君想ふ！
Yomosugara Kimi Omou!
僕が生まれる前よりも
Even before I was born,
ずっと昔から続くように
continuing from long ago,
そういつも傷付け合って
always hurting each other
また愛し合うのさ
and loving each other once again.
でまた愛しちゃうのさ
And I fall in love all over again,
今夜も仕事の遠くにまた ちょっと疲れてたとしたって
even if I'm feeling a little tired from work tonight,
そう僕も他人事なんかじゃないわかってるのさ
I know I'm not just a bystander either.
明けない夜はないと
There's no such thing as an endless night,
夜明け前がただ暗いと この先に待つ明日がそんなに輝くもんかな
it's just that right before dawn is the darkest.
今 I Love You で始まる僕らをもっと照らしてくれよ
Now, let our story starting with an "I Love You" shine even brighter!
変わらない愛や希望の類もまだ信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in unchanging love and hope.
ほら I Miss You って諦めムードでも おっけ飛ばして行けよ
Look, even in a "give up and say I Miss You" mood, keep going!
時代が暗い話題が街ゆくけど 愛を歌う もう Yeah Yeah Yeah
Even though the times are gloomy, I'll sing of love. Oh yeah!
みんな楽しんでってな
Everyone, have a good time!
ああ僕がトロにたらんことで いつも悩んだりしてるのは
Ah, the reason I'm always worrying over trivial things—
言っちゃえばアダムとイブからもう決まってたのさ
frankly speaking, it was already decided since Adam and Eve.
なんとなく恋に落ちて いつの間にか本気だって 張り裂けsounding胸の奥を打ち明けたくなっちゃうな
Falling in love somehow, realizing I was serious, I want to bare my heart.
今 I Love You で始まる僕らをもっと照らしてくれよ
Now, let our story starting with an "I Love You" shine even brighter!
イメージ通りに運ばぬものとしても信じてみたいのさ
Even if things don't go as I imagined, I still want to believe.
ほら I Miss You って賞味期限がある Oh Yes 急かしてくれよ
Look, "I Miss You" has an expiration date, so hurry me along!
時代が暗い未来が待ち受けど 愛を歌う方へ Yeah
Even though a dark future awaits, toward where we sing of love, yeah.
あ啊 どうか夜明けまで 君の声が聴きたい Oh Yeah
Ah, please, I want to hear your voice until dawn, oh yeah.
愛いつも相も変わり映えなくてさ
Love is always the same without much change,
あ僕ら同じことで悩んだり 悲しんだり 笑ったりして乗りにゃ 分かり合うのはそう簡単じゃない
we worry, grieve, and laugh over the same things, but understanding isn't easy.
ただこんなにも君とリンクして 重なっていく
Yet, overlapping and linking so much with you,
今 I Love You で始まる僕らをもっと照らしてくれよ
now, let our story starting with an "I Love You" shine even brighter!
変わらない愛や希望の類もまだ信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in unchanging love and hope.
ほら I Miss You って諦めムードでも おっけ飛ばして行けよ
Look, even in a "give up and say I Miss You" mood, keep going!
時代が暗い話題が街ゆくけど 愛を歌う もう Yeah Yeah
Even though the times are gloomy, I'll sing of love, oh yeah!
あ僕が生まれる前よりもずっと昔から続くように そういつも傷つけあってまた愛しちゃうのさ
Ah, as if continuing from long before I was born, we always hurt and love again.
愛 愛 愛 愛 愛 愛 愛 愛
Love, love, love, love, love, love, love, love!
せーの！一箇所！
Ready, go! One spot!
歌詞間違えた！すみませんでした！うわああ！
I got the lyrics wrong! I'm so sorry! Whoa!
やっちまった！やっちまった！手遅れだ！手遅れだ、やっちまったよ！
I messed up! It's too late! I really messed up!
おいおいおいおいおい すみませんでした！
Hey hey hey hey hey, I'm so sorry!
でも最高に楽しい！笑え、笑え！
But it's super fun! Laugh, laugh!
あっで 途中と思ったけど ちょっと あの 薄かしてみました
Ah, I thought midway, but I tried glossing over it a bit.
すみませんでした 本当に 申し訳ない！
I'm really sorry, I'm so sorry!
次の曲まだあるので ちょっとその前に
Since there's still a next song, right before that,
み 水とか飲んでも いいかな？
would it be okay if I drank some water or something?
お水飲んでも いいかな？いい？
Is it okay if I drink water? Is it?
うま！
Delicious!
水がうめぇじゃ 生命の源なんだじゃ
Water is so good, it's the source of life.
ありがとうね いややっぱ緊張するね
Thank you. Man, it really makes me nervous!
では はよこくちも 聞きたいと思うので 次の曲
Well, since you probably want to hear the announcements, the next song—
言ってもいいですか？言ってもいいですか？
can I say it? Can I say it?
準備いいですか？
Are you ready?
OK! では、
Okay! Now then,
いきましょう！
Let's go!
ヴィラン！
Villain!
きっと手を繋ぐだけでゾッとする
I'm sure we freak them out just by holding hands
馬鹿げた競争（ラットレース）一抜けたら通報される
You're reported when you opt out of the rat race
ミュータントじゃない ただの僕さ XとかYとか
I'm not a mutant, just me, X or Y or whatever
べき論者様は善悪多頭飼い
Moralizers keep multiple heads of good and evil
僕が君を“侵害”するって言いふらしている
Going around saying I'm infringing on you
Oh... Mr. Crazy Villain Villain
夜行性の花弁
Nocturnal petals
違う服着て君の前では男子のフリする
Wearing different clothes, pretending to be a boy in front of you
拝啓 Dr. Durand-Durand
Dear Dr. Durand-Durand
迎えにきてください
Please come pick me up
顔も知らない誰かにとって僕はもうヴィラン
For someone who doesn't know my face, I'm already a villain
蛇足ライフ 挙句の果てに
Detested life, eventually
逸脱の性をまたも経隠す
Desperately covering up my deviant nature again
雄蕊と雌蕊じゃ立ち行かないの？
Can't get anywhere with stamens and pistils?
ねぇ知ってんのかい 乱歩という作家のことを
Hey, do you know the author named Ranpo?
Import you 造花も果ては実を結ぶ
Import you, even artificial flowers will bear fruit
ぶれっつんじゃねぇよ 多種多様な性
Don't be so sure, such diverse genders
愛しい哀しい話をしようぜ ゼラチン質の「で？」
Let's talk about lovely, sad stories, a gelatinous "So what?"
Mr. Crazy Villain Villain 可能性に幸あれ
Mr. Crazy Villain Villain, all the best to possibilities
僕のハートは1LDK 嫉妬くらいはさせてよ
My heart's a 1LDK apartment, at least let me be jealous
Hi there 黙ってYOLO
Hi there, shut up and YOLO
微熱愛でいいのに
Even though a mild feverish love would do
誰もし知らない 知られたくない皮膚の下
Nobody knows, under my skin where I don't want them to know
素晴らしき悪党共に見参 骨まで演じ切ってやれ悪辣に
Behold the wonderful scoundrels, play the role to the bone, viciously
Oh... Mr. Crazy Villain Villain
夜行性の花弁
Nocturnal petals
違う服着て君の前では男子のフリする
Wearing different clothes, pretending to be a boy in front of you
拝啓 Dr. Durand-Durand 迎えにきてください
Dear Dr. Durand-Durand, please come pick me up
顔も知らない誰かにとって僕はもうヴィラン
For someone who doesn't know my face, I'm already a villain
蛇足ライフ 挙句の果てに
Detested life, eventually
逸脱の性をまたも経隠す
Desperately covering up my deviant nature again
挙句の果てのヴィラン
The villain at the very end of it all
イェーイ！
Yeah!
来てくれた本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming!
や、やっぱり歌は難しい 本当に難しいけど
Man, singing is really hard, truly hard, but
楽しい！特にみんなにこうやって聞いてもらって同じ時間を共有してもらうことが本当に 本当にかけがえない時間だなと思います。
It's fun! Especially having everyone listen like this and sharing the same time feels truly, truly irreplaceable.
では、ここであれいきましょうかね。まず告知！なんと！
Now then, let's make an announcement here. First, announcement! Guess what!
角巻わためのお誕生日記念のグッズがなんと！
Tsunomaki Watame's birthday commemorative goods are, wow!
出ます！出ます！出ます！
Coming out! Coming out! Coming out!
角巻わため 誕生日記念2021 6月6日 販売開始
[Announcement: Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Commemoration 2021 - On sale June 6]
を考えて
Think about it...
おにまん！
Oniman!
そして！
And then!
記念グッズ2種…
Two types of commemorative goods...
これは個別の画像があったりしますかな？
Will there be individual images for these?
ぷるり！
Pururi!
なんと！フウミママ描き下ろしあったかブランケットー！
And behold! A warm blanket illustrated by Fuumi-mama!
ぷるり！
Pururi!
多分これね、今日買っていただいて、届くまでにね、ちょっと時間がかかると思うんですよ。
You'll probably buy it today, and it'll take some time for it to arrive, I think.
こう涼しくなった頃にこのブランケットがね、届くんじゃないかなという想定で、ブランケット今回作らせていただきました。
I figured it might arrive around when it gets cooler, so we decided to make this blanket with that timing in mind.
そして！
And then!
ぷるり！
Pururi!
ぷるりの音が面白くて笑ってしまうけど
The sound of 'pururi' is so funny, it makes me laugh, but
これこれこれ！これ目玉商品ですよ、これ！
this, this, this! This is the star product, this!
原田たけひと先生描き下ろしわためナイトFever!!温感マグカップ！
The 'Watame Night Fever!!' thermal mug illustrated by Takehito Harada!
知ってる？原田たけひと先生って、みんな知ってますか？
Do you know? Takehito Harada-sensei, does everyone know him?
あの、わためね、大好きな日本一ソフトウェアさんの
You know, Watame loves Nippon Ichi Software...
あの、わかるでしょ？わためも声とかさせてもらった
You know, right? Watame even got to do voices and stuff
ディスガイア！
in Disgaea!
そう、ディスガイアのね、イラストを担当されてる方なんですよ。
Yes, she's the person in charge of the illustrations for Disgaea.
そう！なんと今回引き受けていただきまして、描いていただくことができました！
Yes! And somehow she agreed to take it on this time, and we got her to draw it!
いえーい！
Yay!
しかも、9時50分もうね、多分、ブースのページはね、オープンしてると思うので、販売は10時からになるんですけど、よかったらそちらもチェックしてみてください。
And also, at 9:50, the booth page should already be open, and sales start at 10, so please check that out if you'd like.
で、これが、冷たい状態だとわためがね、暗闇でこうポツンと一人でフィーバーしてるんだけど
And when this is cold, Watame is just fevering all alone in the dark,
あの、あったかい飲み物をね、入れてもらいますと、なんと、ステージと、あとわためいとと、ライトとかがね、ぱーっと浮かび上がってきて
but if you pour a warm drink into it, amazingly, the stage, Watameites, and lights all float up into view,
華やかなステージをみんなで一緒に作り上げるっていう、そういう、ライブとかしたいねっていう、夢、夢？希望？も込めて
with the dream and hope of building a gorgeous stage together with everyone, wanting to hold a live concert like that,
このマグカップ作らせていただきました！
we had this mug made!
あとね、特典もありまして
And also, there are special bonuses,
ぷるり！ぷるりない！
Pururi! No pururi!
これはこの、ボイス4種類セットとグッズ2種類セット、全部セットですね、買っていただいた方に、フウミママ描き下ろしイラストポストカード
For those who buy the 4-voice set and 2-goods set—the complete set—we have an illustration postcard illustrated by Fuumi-mama,
ブランケットのとはちょっと表情が違うんですけど、それになんと、わため直筆サインも！いたしまーす！
whose expression is a little different from the blanket's, and it even comes with Watame's handwritten signature! We'll do that!
しかも、数量限定しません！
And what's more, no quantity limits!
全部書きます！なので、争奪戦は起きないと思うので、10時からの販売ね、そんな焦らないで、戦争しないでね。
I'll write all of them! So, I don't think a scramble will happen, so for the 10 AM sales, don't rush too much, don't start a war.
はい、数量限定しません！
Yes, no quantity limits!
いや、もしとんでもねえぐらい来たら、ちょっとこれ以上はって、運営さんストップがかかるかもしれないけど、一応今のところ制限なしです。
Well, if an insane amount of orders come in, management might put a stop to it saying 'no more than this,' but for now, there are no restrictions.
そしてあと、特典ボイスもついてきます、これが、まとめて1万円かな？全部セットで1万円となっております。
And also, bonus voice tracks are included—this comes bundled for 10,000 yen? It's 10,000 yen for the complete set.
あとね、個別販売も今回ありまして、「マグカップだけもう一個欲しいな」とか、「ブランケットだけもう一個欲しいな」とか、そういった方単品で買っていただくこともできます。
And also, individual sales are available this time too—for those who think 'I want one more mug' or 'I want one more blanket,' you can buy them individually.
あ、転売ヤー気をつける！一日何枚ずつとかでやってけば大丈夫だと思うんだよね。そう、1万円となっております。よかったら
Ah, watch out for scalpers! I think if you do a few each day, it'll be fine. Right, it's 10,000 yen. If you'd like,
このあと10時から買ってくだしゃい！お願いします。
please buy it starting at 10 AM! Please.
そして、このあと、告知に、10時15分からこれはもう枠立ってるんですけど、プレミア公開の動画が、怪物歌ってみた！
And then, after this, for the announcement, starting at 10:15—the room is already set up—the premiere video of singing 'Kaibutsu'!
素晴らしい世界に今日も乾杯
Cheers to this wonderful world once again today
ねぇ、
Hey,
これは
this is...
ねぇ、パコパコ！
Hey, Pako Pako!
お世話になってるみんなへ
To everyone who has taken care of me,
わためからのプレゼントになるか分からないけどプレゼントです
I don't know if this counts as a present from Watame, but here is a present! (Laughs)
素晴らしい世界に今日も乾杯
Cheers to this wonderful world today again.
街に飛び交う笑い声も
The laughter echoing through the city as well—
見て見ぬふりをしてるだけの作りのもんさ
it's just a facade, pretending not to notice.
気圧されそうだ
It's almost overwhelming.
クラクラするほどの良い匂いがツンと刺した鼻の奥
An intoxicatingly sweet scent pierced deep into my nose,
目を覚ます本能のまま
following my awakening instincts.
今日は誰の番だ
Whose turn is it today?
この世界で何が出来るのか
What can be done in this world?
僕には何が出来るのか
What can I do?
ただその真っ黒な目から涙溢れ落ちないように
Just so tears won't overflow from those pitch-black eyes,
願う未来に何度でもずっと噛み付く
I'll keep biting at the future I wish for, over and over.
この間違いだらけの世界の中で君には笑ってほしい
In this world full of mistakes, I want you to smile.
もう誰も傷付けない強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become strong enough not to hurt anyone anymore,
僕が僕でいられるように
so that I can stay true to myself.
素晴らしい世界は今日も安泰
This wonderful world is safe again today.
街に渦巻く悪い噂も
Even the bad rumors swirling around the city—
知らない知らないふりして目を逸した
I pretended not to know and looked away.
正気の沙汰じゃないな
It's sheer madness.
真面目に着飾った行進鳴らす足音が弾む
The marching footsteps, dressed up in earnest, echo and bound.
行き先は消えない消えない味が染み付いている
Where they lead is stained with an indelible, lingering taste—
裏側の世界
the world on the other side.
清く正しく生きること
To live purely and righteously,
誰も悲しませずに生きること
to live without causing sorrow to anyone,
はみ出さず真っ直ぐに生きること
to live straight without stepping out of line—
それが間違いじゃないで生きること
is that living without making mistakes?
ありのまま生きることが正義か
Is living as you are justice?
騙し騙し生きるのは正義か
Is living by deceiving justice?
僕の在るべき姿とはなんだ
What is the way I should be?
本当の僕は誰者なんだ
Who is my true self?
教えて教えて
Tell me, tell me.
今日も
Today once again,
答えのない世界の中で
in a world with no answers,
あ、願っているんだよ
ah, I am wishing for it.
不器用だけれどいつまでも君とただ
Though clumsy, I just want to stay with you forever,
笑っていたいんだ
laughing together.
あ、跳ねる心臓が体揺らし叫ぶんだよ
Ah, my bounding heart shakes my body and cries out,
今こそ動き出せ
"Move right now!"
弱い自分を何度でもずっと噛み尽くす
I'll devour my weak self over and over again.
この間違いだらけの世界の中で君には笑ってほしいから
In this world full of mistakes, because I want you to smile,
もう誰も泣かないように強く強くなりたいんだよ
so no one will ever cry again, I want to become strong, strong.
僕が僕でいられるようにただ君を守るそのために
So I can stay true to myself, just to protect you,
走る走る走るんだよ僕の中の僕を超える
I'll run, run, run, surpassing the "me" inside of me.
創世のアクエリオン！
Genesis of Aquarion!
世界の始まりの日 生命の木の下で くじらたちの声の遠い残響 二人で聞いた
The day the world began, under the tree of life, we heard together the distant echoes of the whales' voices.
失くしたものすべて 愛したものすべて この手に抱きしめて 現在はどこを彷徨い行くのか
Embracing everything we've lost, everything we've loved, in our hands, where are we wandering now in the present?
不死なる瞬き持つ 魂
A soul with an immortal blink of an eye—
傷付かないで 僕の羽根
do not get hurt, my wings.
この気持ち知るため 生まれてきた
I was born just to know this feeling.
一万年と二千年前から愛してる
I've loved you since 12,000 years ago,
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
and since 8,000 years passed, I've missed you even more.
一億と二千年後も愛してる
I'll love you 100,000,000 and 2,000 years from now too.
君を知ったその日から 彼の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I came to know you, music has never ceased in my hell.
世界が終わる前に 生命が終わる前に
Before the world ends, before life ends,
耳すませた 海神の記憶
I listened closely to the memories of the sea god.
失意にのまれ 立ち尽くす 麗しき月
Swallowed by despair, the beautiful moon stands still.
よみがえれ 永遠に澄まぬ光 汚されないで 君の夢
Revive, light that will never run dry; do not let your dreams be tainted.
祈り宿しながら 生まれてきた
I was born with a prayer dwelling within.
一万年と二千年前から愛してる
I've loved you since 12,000 years ago,
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
and since 8,000 years passed, I've missed you even more.
一億と二千年後も愛してる
I'll love you 100,000,000 and 2,000 years from now too.
君を知ったその日から 彼の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I came to know you, music has never ceased in my hell.
愛してるぜ!
I love you!
世界が終わる前に 生命が終わる前に
Before the world ends, before life ends,
眠るなげき解いて 君の香り 抱きしめたいよ
I want to untie my slumbering grief and embrace your fragrance.
耳すませたのは わずみの記憶
What I listened closely to was the memory of our bond.
漆黒にとまれ 立ち尽くす わざしずき
Pausing in pitch darkness, standing still...
蘇えれ 永久に視たれぬ光
Revive, light that will never fade away!
汚されないで 君の夢
Do not let your dreams be tainted.
祈り宿しながら 生まれてきた
I was born with a prayer dwelling within.
一万年と二千年前から愛してる
I've loved you since 12,000 years ago,
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
and since 8,000 years passed, I've missed you even more.
一億と二千年後も愛してる
I'll love you 100,000,000 and 2,000 years from now too.
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I came to know you, music has never ceased in my hell.
ナイス! 君を知ったその日から
Nice! Since the day I came to know you...
世界の始まりの日 生命の樹の下で
On the day the world began, beneath the tree of life,
くじらたちの声の遠い残響 二人で聞いた
we listened together to the distant echoes of the whales' voices.
君が繰り返し大人になって 何度も何度も遠くへ行って 見守る僕が眠れない僕が
As you repeatedly grew up and went far away time and time again, I watched over you, unable to sleep,
僕がくしゃくしゃになったとしても
even if I became a crumpled mess...
君の名を歌うために
To sing your name...
一万年と二千年前から愛してる
I've loved you from 12,000 years ago,
8000年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
and from 8,000 years past, I grew to love you even more.
一億と二千年あとも愛してる
I'll love you 100 million and 2,000 years from now too,
君を知ったその日から
ever since the day I came to know you.
一万年と二千年前から
From 12,000 years ago...
愛してる
I love you.
8000年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
From 8,000 years past, I grew to love you even more.
一億と二千年あとも愛してる
I'll love you 100 million and 2,000 years from now too.
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Ever since the day I knew you, music never ceased in my hell.
沢山の応援も どんどん突っ走りますのでよろしくお願いします 今日は本当にありがとう
Thank you all so much for your support! I'll keep charging forward, so please keep supporting me! Thank you so much today!